Guide to the Ernie O'Malley Papers AIA.060
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series VIII. Nationalistic Material, 1643-1966, undated
  - Dial Eireann: Official correspondence relating to the peace negotiations, June-September 1921, Oct 1921 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "The Drama of Eight Days June 22-29, 1922" (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - "The Duty of the Hour" by Diarmuid Figgis from The Sinn Fein Cathecism (Messrs. Whelan and Son, Ormond Quay), circa 1920 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Eire: The Irish Nation partial issues - April 7, April 21, July 23, September 6, 1923-1924 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Erskine Childers" (Leslie Smith and Co., London), undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - "Heads Up" flier (Ernie O'Malley writing on verso), Jun 28, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - "Irish Leaders of our time" pamphlet series (An Cosantoir, Dublin), 1945 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - The Irish Review Vol. 1, No. 5 (signed by Ernie O'Malley in jail), Dec 23, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Is Ireland a danger to England?: The strategic question examined" (reprinted from The Irish Bulletin, London, July 21, 1929), undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - "A letter from the Earl of Westmoreland British Viceroy to Ireland to William Pitt, Prime Minister of England" (Ben Franklin Bureau, Chicago), Jan 18, 1792 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - "Letter of the Supreme Council of the Confederate Catholics to the Mayor of Kilkenny", Sep 22, 1643 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Local security force: Organisation, function and duties of the local security force", undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - National Assocation of Old I.R.A. appeal for funds, circa 1930s (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - "The National Situation" inaugural Sinn Fein address J.J. O'Kelly, October 1936 (Sinn Fein Standing Committee), Oct 1936 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - The Orange Card (All-Party Anti-Partition Conference, Dublin), circa 1949 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Poblacht na hEireann War News No. 106 [Dublin?], Dec 2, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Poblacht na hEireann The Republic of Ireland Vol 1. nos 22-27, May 25, 1922-Jun 29, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Postscript" by Philip Noel-Baker, Parliamentary Secretary to the Minister of War Transport, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Proclamation: Offer of Amnesty 8 February, 1923 Dublin (Gen. Richard Mulcahy), Feb 8, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Register of Prohibited Publications (as of September 30, 1935) Saorstat Eireann; Censorship of Publications Act, 1929 (Stationery Office, Dublin) (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - "The Republic of Ireland addresses His Holiness the Pope (Sinn Fein Standing Committee), 1929 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Republicans Stop Talking! Neutrals Shut Up! Spies and Informers Beware! (flier during Civil war), undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Robert Emmet's Speech from the dock 1803 (Irish Book Bureau, Dublin), undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - "Sean McCaughey - The Truth" (Republican Prisoners' Release Association, Dublin), 1940s (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - "Sinn Fein Courts in Operation" by W.H. Brayden, in Journal of the American Bar Association, Sep 1920 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Saoirse na hEireann, Irish Freedom: clippings, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - War News No. 5 Jul 1, 19__, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Weekly News Bulletin (from Friends of Irish Freedom, New York) Oct 10, Oct 19, Oct 24, Oct 31, Oct 1921 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Weekly Freeman "Dublin Castle Secrets", Nov 22, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings: The Evening Telegraph (Dublin), Apr 1, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Newspaper Clippings: fragments, 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Series IX. Jack B. Yeats, 1904-1980
  The series contains correspondence, articles, clippings, invitations, cancelled checks, receipts, notes, exhibition catalogs, stamps and photographs collected by Ernie O'Malley relating to Jack B. Yeats, as well as, items relating to Yeats' father, John B. Yeats, and brother, William Butler Yeats. Items in this series are of both a personal and professional nature. O'Malley and Jack B. Yeats met in Ireland during the 1930s and developed a friendship that lasted until their deaths in 1957. In addition to being a patron of Yeats' artwork, O'Malley served on the Jack B. Yeats National Loan Exhibition Committee and authored the introduction for the exhibition's catalog in 1945. Throughout the course of their friendship Yeats gifted O'Malley various pencil sketches and writings by John B. Yeats, in addition to several letters written by the elder Yeats to his other son, William Butler Yeats. Other items include Yeats materials collected by Ernie O'Malley's son, Cormac O'Malley.
  - Index to Jack B. Yeats material, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Article: "Fifty Years of Irish Painting" Thomas MacGreevy in The Capuchin Annual, undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Article: "Jack B. Yeats: An Impression" by Mairin Allen, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Article "The Yeats Exhibition" C.P. Curran in The Capuchin Annual, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Article: "Three Historical Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" [Thomas MacGreevy] in The Capuchin Annual, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Article: "Visits to Jack Yeats" John Rothenstein in New English Review, Jul 1946 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Commemorative Stamps: Jack B. Yeats (on postcard addressed to COM), 1971 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - "The Connaught Toast" Cuala Press card; EOM correspondence on verso, undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence: Yeats, Jack B. to EOM, 1939-1951 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence: Yeats, John B. to William Butler Yeats (Willie), 1916-1919 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Envelope - addressed to EOM with Jack B. Yeats insignia, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Exhibition of Later Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Victor Waddington Galleries, Dublin, Nov 1943 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Jack Yeats: Irish Expressionist" Birmingham Museum of Art, Birmingham, Alabama, Mar 15, 1980-Apr 30, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Jack B. Yeats National Loan Exhibition" National College of Art, Dublin, Jun 1945-Jul 1945 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Later Paintings by Jack Yeats" at the Victor Waddington Galleries, Dublin (annotations and signature of EOM), Mar 1945 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Pictures by Anne Yeats" annotated, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Victor Waddington Galleries, Dublin, Mar 1945 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Victor Waddington Galleries, Dublin, Oct 1946-Nov 1946 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Victor Waddington Galleries, Dublin, Feb 1955 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Catalog: "A Small Collection of Later Work of Jack B. Yeats" The Contemporary Picture Gallery, Dublin, Oct 27, 1941-Nov 8, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Catalog and Invitation: "Paintings by Jack B. Yeats" Wildenstein and Co., Ltd. Gallery, London, Feb 13, 1946-Mar 9, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Invitation: Cuala Press December 5-6, 194_, 1940s (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Invitation: Jack B. Yeats to Ernie O'Malley and wife for November 5 1943 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Invitations to performances of "A Night at the Inn" and "La La Noo" (plays), Apr 1942-May 1942 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1904-1952 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Notebook: Sketches and critiques of Yeats exhibition, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Paintings: reproductions of, from publications, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Photograph - photocopy of reproduction of Thomas MacGreevy at Yeats Exhibit, circa 1947 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Publication: The Dublin Magazine volume 1, number 6, Jan 1924 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Publication: The Dublin Magazine volume 1, number 8, Mar 1924 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Publication: "The Treasure of the Garden" by Jack B. Yeats (play; published by Elkin Mathews, London), undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Yeats, John B.: Essays / Letters, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Yeats, John B.: Essays / Letters, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Yeats Paintings in Ireland: Lists by Ernie O'Malley, circa 9145 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Yeats Paintings: List by Ernie O'Malley, circa 1945 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Yeats Paintings: Sales history, circa 1945 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Series X. Diaries, Notes and Research, 1922-1963
  This series contains diaries, journals, notebooks, loose notes and research by Ernie O'Malley contextualizing his literary output and body of work. Items in this series reflect the commentary, criticisms, critiques and general notes taken by O'Malley on a variety of topics including art, literature, poetry and history, and provide insight into his research methodology and writing process. Most notebooks in this series are untitled, however, some notebooks bear the letters "P" indicating painting, or "I" for Ireland. Of special interest in this series are O'Malley's diaries from his travels in the United States and Mexico, as well as, notebooks relating to his military career. See the accompanying index for an itemized listing, description and full summary of each notebook in this series. Additional notebooks and notes may be found in Series 1: Works and Series 12: Art Materials.
  The series is arranged chronologically, with Notes arranged alphabetically by subject and filed at the end of the series.
  - Index to Diaries, Notes and Research, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    Diaries, notes and research are arranged chronologically. Diaries and notebooks comprise the first part of the series, arranged by known date and then by items with known date spans. The notes are arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Notebook: reading lists, 1922-1927 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Diary Pyrenees I, 1924-1926 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Diary Pyrenees II, 1924-1926 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Diary Pyrenees with annotations (typed), 1924-1926 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Notebook: Trip to Italy, 1925-1926 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Noteook: Trip to Italy, 1925-1926 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Diary, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Diary: United States, 1928-1929 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Diary: Irish Press [activites in the United States] I, 1928-1929 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Diary: Irish Press [activites in the United States] II (photocopy), 1928-1929 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Diary: California, untitled, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Notebook: some New Mexico, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Notebooks, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Notebooks, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Diary: Boston and New York, 1933-1935 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Diary: Various locations I, 1935-1951 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Diary: Various locations II (transcript of), 1935-1951 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Diary, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Notebook; notes in Ireland, addresses, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Diary, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: Land (the Campanile writing tablet), Jul 1942 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: Details of Farm at Burrishoole Lodge in Newport, Co. Mayo (bound), 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: "No. 3 Farm Accounts Burrishoole Lodge", 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: "Burrishoole Lodge Farm Book No. 4", Mar 1944-Sep 1944 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Notebook: "Burrishoole Lodge Farm Book No. 5", Sep 1944-Mar 1944 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Notebook: Burrishoole Lodge Farm information; lists of purchases and of books and records (music) [not listed in original inventory], 1940-1945 (Box 10, Folder 9A)
  - Notebook: "Anatomy Farm Book No.", 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Diary, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Diary, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Notebook (untitled), Mar 1953-Aug 1953 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Notebook (untitled), 1956 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, circa 1920-1925 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Notebook: "Books and Comments", circa 1923-1924 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Notebook: untitled "A", circa 1926-1928 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Notebook: untitled "B", circa 1926-1928 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Notebook: untitled "C", circa 1926-1928 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1927 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Notebook: "Ireland", circa 1927-1928 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Notebook: "Painting", circa 1928-1929 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1928-1929 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Notebook: "S", circa 1930-1935 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Notebook: "I", circa 1932 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Notebook: "N", circa 1932 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Notebook: "G", circa 1932-1935 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Notebook: "Geography: Asia", circa 1930s (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Notebook: "H", circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: "I" I, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: "I" II, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: "I" III, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: "I" IV, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Notebook: "I", circa 1932-1937 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: "L/I" I, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Notebook: "L/I" II, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Notebook: "LR", circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Notebook "My/I", corca 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Notebook "N", circa Feb 1929 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Notebook "N" I, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Notebook "N" II, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Notebook "P", circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Notebook "Russia", circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Notebook "Songs", circa 1927-1932 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Notebook: untitled I, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Notebook: untitled II, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Notebook: untitled III, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Notebook: untitled IV, circa 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Notebook: "Cat", circa 1932-1937 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Notebook: "E", circa 1932-1937 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Notebook: "G" artists, circa 1935-1937 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Notebook: "S", circa 1937 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1937 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Notebook: "F", circa 1933 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1933-1934 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: "E", circa 1934 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: "I", circa 1935 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: "I", circa 1935-1937 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: "L", circa 1935-1937 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1935-1937 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: "I", circa 1936-1937 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1936-1937 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1936-1938 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Notebook: "P", circa 1937 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Notebook: "T", circa 1937 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Notebook: "D", circa 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Notebook: "FL", corca 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Notebook: "Mayo", circa 1937-1939 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Notebook: "SP" "I", corca 1937-1939 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Notebook: untitled "I" "P", circa 1938 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1938 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1938 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Notebook: "Notebook on books on Ireland" I, circa 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Notebook: "Notebook on books on Ireland" II, circa 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Notebook: "SC 1589-93", circa 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Notebook: "SC 1589-95", circa 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Notebook: "SC 1557-1603", circa 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Notebook: "Researchers in the S. of Ireland", circa 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Notebook: untitled I, circa 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: untitled II, circa 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: untitled III, circa 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: "Carew", circa 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1938 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Notebook: untitled I, circa 1939 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: untitled II, circa 1939 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1939-1944 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Notebook: "Studies on books", circa 1940-1944 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Notebook: untitled I, circa 1940-1949 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Notebook: untitled II, circa 1940-1949 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Notebook: untitled III, circa 1940-1949 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Notebook: untitled IV, circa 1940-1949 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Notebook: "V", circa 1940-1949 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Notebook: "A", circa 1942-1955 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1944 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1944-1946 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1945-1947 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1945-1948 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: "75", circa 1946 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1946-1948 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Notebook "3", circa 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: "Book II James Joyce", circa 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1947-1950 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Notebook: "Irish Painting", circa 1950-1957 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1950-1957 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Notebook: "book lists", circa 1954 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Notebook: "Books", circa 1954 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Notebook: "Irish Books / booklists", circa 1954 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Notebook: "Irish Lit", circa 1954 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Notebook: "WR", circa 1954 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1954 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1954 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Notebook: "Lit General", circa 1955 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1955 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Notebook: "Book lists", circa 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Notebook: "Book lists", circa 1956 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1956 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Notebook: "Armada", undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Notebook: "Clare Ennis and Quinn Abbeys", undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Notebook: "Clare", circa 1939, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: "Cross Slabs", circa 1939, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: "P", circa 1939, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1932-1935, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1936-1938, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1937-1938, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1937-1939, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1944, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1947, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1956, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Notebook: untitled, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Notes: Autobiography I, circa 1944-1948 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Notes: Autobiography II, circa 1944-1948 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Notes: Autobiography I, circa 1944-1950 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Notes: Autobiography II, circa 1944-1950 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Notes: Folklore (drawn and painted map), circa 1940, una=dated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Notes: Folklore, circa 1940, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Notes: Folklore I, 1940s (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Notes: Folklore II, 1940s (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Notes: Irish History, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Notes: Irish History, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Notes: Irish History I, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Notes: Irish History II, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Notes: Irish Literature, circa 1929 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Notes: Lists of books read by Ernie O'Malley, 1926-1927 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous I, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous II, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous III, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous IV, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous V, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous VI, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous VII, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous VIII, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Notes: Music, circa 1940-1946 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Notes: Travel Expense, circa 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Notes: untitled, circa 1963 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Notes: untitled [Irish Literature?], 1929-1950 (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Series XI. Clippings and Publicity, 1895-2002
  This series includes newspaper clippings, book reviews, magazine features, advertisements, book covers and correspondence relating to Ernie O'Malley, his literary output and posthumous publications. Many of the clippings in this series were collected by O'Malley and reflect his general interests in art, literature, poetry, theatre and current affairs. Clippings also relate to international affairs and historic events including the Second World War, Spanish Civil War and Anglo-Irish relations. O'Malley collected articles of interest from both American and European newspapers including, The New York Times, Irish Independent and Irish Press. This series also contains clippings detailing O'Malley's funeral, as well as, book reviews and other items pertaining to the publication of On Another Man's Wound and its German translation, Rebellen en Irlande. Additional items in this series relate to the publicity of books published after his death by O'Malley's son Cormac O'Malley and Richard English including Prisoners: The Civil War Letters of Ernie O'Malley and Richard English's Ernie O'Malley: IRA Intellectual.
  The series is arranged chronologically.
  - Index to Clippings and publicity, 2010 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Clippings collected by Ernie O'Malley, 1895-1949 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: various including family, death notice, donation of papers to University College Dublin, 1922-1990 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Clippings collected by Ernie O'Malley (see index for list), 1921-1948 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: wounding and capturing of O'Malley, 1922-1957 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Reviews of Ernie O'Malley books I, 1928-1992 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Reviews of Ernie O'Malley books II, 1928-1992 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Clippings re: Marriage O'Malley-Hooker; society clippings, 1935-1936 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: Irish, English and American press, 1935-1937 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Clippings: Irish, English press including articles on Charles Lindburgh, Eamon DeValera, Fred Aiken, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Clippings: Irish, English and American press, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Clippings: Review of Army without Banners, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Clippings and reviews: International Arts I, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Clippings and reviews: International Arts II, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Clippings and reviews: Arts and similar, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, mostly Irish: Art, History, Current Affairs I, 1936-1948 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, mostly Irish: Art, History, Current Affairs II, 1936-1948 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, mostly Irish: Art, History, Current Affairs III, 1936-1948 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: International Affairs, Spain, Art, Ireland, 1936-1961 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Clippings: reviews Army without Banners - New York, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Clippings: reviews Army without Banners - Massachusetts, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Clippings: reviews Army without Banners - United States, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Clippings and publicity: On Another Man's Wound (Irish Press), 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Clippings and publicity: On Another Man's Wound, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Clippings and publicity: On Another Man's Wound, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Clippings: German Language, 1938-1939 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Clippings: Reviews of Ernie O'Malley and works, 1940-2002 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Clippings - Irish Press, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 25)